let mcqQuestions = [{ "questionText": "Realism: the thesis that", "answers": ["some things are mind-independent", "everything is mind-independent", "some things are mind-dependent", "everything is mind-dependent"], "answer": "some things are mind-independent" }, { "questionText": "Skepticism: the view that", "answers": ["knowledge and even reasonable belief is unattainable", "values tend to undermine themselves", "the world is a construction of the mind", "nothing has value or meaning"], "answer": "knowledge and even reasonable belief is unattainable" }, { "questionText": "Existentialists view the meaning of life as something", "answers": ["we have to define for ourselves", "given to us by God", "depending on society and culture", "a matter of contributing to the common good of mankind"], "answer": "we have to define for ourselves" }, { "questionText": "Bellow's title \"Seize the Day\" alludes to a poem by", "answers": ["Horace", "Shakespeare", "Eliot", "Virgil"], "answer": "Horace" }, { "questionText": "Expressivism: the view that moral judgments are most akin to", "answers": ["interjections", "commands", "questions", "declarative statements"], "answer": "interjections" }, { "questionText": "Natural law theory is a form of", "answers": ["moral realism", "expressivism", "emotivism", "subjectivism"], "answer": "moral realism" }, { "questionText": "A model of reality that it's easy to mistake for reality itself:", "answers": ["hyperreality", "idealism", "the original position", "the myth of the given"], "answer": "hyperreality" }, { "questionText": "Heidegger's concept of Geworfenheit:", "answers": ["thrownness, having no choice of my circumstances", "radical freedom and thus radical responsibility", "social control and alignment with one ideology", "the range of possibilities open to me in the future"], "answer": "thrownness, having no choice of my circumstances" }, { "questionText": "The revolution deposing the Shah in Iran, the ascension of the Khmer Rouge in Cambodia, and the USSR's invasion of Afghanistan occurred during the Presidency of", "answers": ["Jimmy Carter", "Ronald Reagan", "Richard Nixon", "Lyndon Baines Johnson"], "answer": "Jimmy Carter" }, { "questionText": "‘Nazi’ is short for", "answers": ["National Socialist Workers’ Party", "National Association for Reform", "National Unity Party", "Party for a Greater Germany"], "answer": "National Socialist Workers’ Party" }, { "questionText": "Stalin’s aim during the Great Purge, 1935–1939: to destroy", "answers": ["the Party", "the bourgeoisie", "the kulaks", "Nazi sympathesizers"], "answer": "the Party" }, { "questionText": "Saul Bellow’s view of the Romantic ideas that \"every individual had to re-invent himself and everything that surrounded him in an original way. As if to live were an act of genius, as though we had no resemblance whatever to people who preceded us.\"", "answers": ["Obviously wrong", "Obviously right", "Partially true", "True but misleading"], "answer": "Obviously wrong" }, { "questionText": "The ancient philosophical attitude embodied in the slogan, “Seize the Day”:", "answers": ["Epicureanism", "Stoicism", "Skepticism", "Platonism"], "answer": "Epicureanism" }, { "questionText": "“This was typical of Wilhelm. After much thought and hesitation and debate he invariably took the course he had rejected innumerable times.” Bellow here describes his character as suffering from", "answers": ["weakness of will", "subjectivism", "noncognitivism", "existentialism"], "answer": "weakness of will" }, { "questionText": "Stalin's collectivization of agriculture slaughtered ten million people; ten million were forced to Siberia, and another ten million were sent to concentration camps. The rest:", "answers": ["lost all property, becoming, in effect, slaves", "became wealthy kulaks", "became members of the Party", "were charged in show trials"], "answer": "lost all property, becoming, in effect, slaves" }, { "questionText": "Kolakowski: \"probably the most massive war-like operation ever conducted by a state against its own citizens.\"", "answers": ["Stalin's collectivization of agriculture", "the Holocaust", "the invasion of Poland", "the Holodomor"], "answer": "Stalin's collectivization of agriculture" }, { "questionText": "The Holodomor:", "answers": ["Stalin's man-made Ukrainian famine", "Hitler's attempted extermination of the Jews", "the collectivization of Soviet agriculture", "the Great Purge"], "answer": "Stalin's man-made Ukrainian famine" }, { "questionText": "The Gulag Archepelago:", "answers": ["a system of prison camps in the Soviet Union", "a chain of islands in the Pacific", "the workers' collectives in the USSR", "Germany's system of death camps"], "answer": "a system of prison camps in the Soviet Union" }, { "questionText": "Playwright Bertold Brecht's response to the Show Trials, and to the disappearance of his own girlfriend on her return to the Soviet Union:", "answers": ["\"The more innocent they are, the more they deserve to die.\"", "\"You can’t make an omelet without breaking eggs.\"", "\"We were all of us up to the elbows in blood.\"", "\"Cowardice has become the norm.\""], "answer": "\"The more innocent they are, the more they deserve to die.\"" }, { "questionText": "Malcolm Muggeridge, having published Winter in Moscow, critical of Stalin, returned to Great Britain to find", "answers": ["he couldn't get a job", "he was promoted to editor", "he had changed British policy toward Stalin", "he had changed British opinion toward Stalin"], "answer": "he couldn't get a job" }, { "questionText": "The Enabling Act, passed in 1933,", "answers": ["gave all legislative power to Hitler and his cabinet", "allowed Roosevelt to add six justices to the Supreme Court", "allowed the Weimar Republic to reform the currency", "reduced the size of the British and French military"], "answer": "gave all legislative power to Hitler and his cabinet" }, { "questionText": "The Night of the Long Knives: the victims were", "answers": ["political opponents of Adolf Hitler", "Trotsky, Bukharin, and other competitors of Josef Stalin", "a group of Russian poets, scientists, and intellectuals", "Italians who opposed Mussolini's March on Rome"], "answer": "political opponents of Adolf Hitler" }, { "questionText": "“I would close every recruiting station, disband the Army and disarm the Air Force. I would abolish the whole dreadful equipment of war and say to the world, ‘Do your worst.’” The author led which political party, in which country?", "answers": ["The Labour Party, United Kingdom", "The Nazi Party, Germany", "The Fascist Party, Italy", "The Democratic Party, United States"], "answer": "The Labour Party, United Kingdom" }, { "questionText": "Paul Johnson writes, “It is of the essence of geopolitics to be able to distinguish between different degrees of evil.” He is arguing that ______ overreacted to ______.", "answers": ["the British and French; Mussolini's invasion of Ethiopia", "the United States; Japan's invasion of China", "Hitler; the Treaty of Versailles", "the British; Hitler's occupation of Austria"], "answer": "the British and French; Mussolini's invasion of Ethiopia" }, { "questionText": "\" I believe this is peace for our time.\"", "answers": ["Neville Chamberlain, after meeting with Hitler in Munich", "Adolf Hitler, after occupying Austria", "Franklin Delano Roosevelt, after the Japanese surrender", "Winston Churchill, after the Battle of Britain"], "answer": "Neville Chamberlain, after meeting with Hitler in Munich" }, { "questionText": "The event that flipped the balance of power in Europe in Germany's favor:", "answers": ["the annexation of the Czech Sudetenland", "the occupation of Austria", "the invasion of Norway", "the militarization of the Rhine"], "answer": "the annexation of the Czech Sudetenland" }, { "questionText": "How much time elapsed between the German invasion of France in 1940 and France's surrender?", "answers": ["6 weeks", "4 years", "2 days", "8 months"], "answer": "6 weeks" }, { "questionText": "The decisive battle of the War in the Pacific, in which Japan lost control of the Pacific Ocean, in June 1942:", "answers": ["Midway", "Stalingrad", "Iwo Jima", "Normandy"], "answer": "Midway" }, { "questionText": "In December 1941, events on two successive days turned the tide against Germany's war effort:", "answers": ["the Russians counterattacked, and the Japanese attacked Pearl Harbor", "the British acquired the Enigma machine, and bombed Berlin", "the Royal Air Force survived the Battle of Britain, and the British Army was evacuated from Dunkirk", "the American's took Guadalcanal, and the Russians won the Battle of Stalingrad"], "answer": "the Russians counterattacked, and the Japanese attacked Pearl Harbor" }, { "questionText": "June 6, 1944:", "answers": ["D-Day, the invasion of Normandy", "the end of the war in the Pacific", "the attack on Pearl Harbor", "the end of the war in Europe"], "answer": "D-Day, the invasion of Normandy" }, { "questionText": "Neville Chamberlain said, “...today I share their disappointment, their indignation, that those hopes have been so wantonly shattered. How can these events this week be reconciled with those assurances which I have read out to you?\" after the German invasion of", "answers": ["Czechoslovakia", "Poland", "Austria", "Norway"], "answer": "Czechoslovakia" }, { "questionText": "Democracy's dilemma, as Churchill sees it:", "answers": ["they refrain from fighting until the odds are against them", "they allow decisions to be made by the uninformed", "the interests of the people's representatives are not those of the people", "they inevitably devolve into tyranny"], "answer": "they refrain from fighting until the odds are against them" }, { "questionText": "Hitler found his early base of support primarily among", "answers": ["university students and professors", "union workers", "government employees", "leaders of German industry"], "answer": "university students and professors" }, { "questionText": "The first act of the Weimar Republic was to", "answers": ["sign the Treaty of Versailles", "print money to meet war debts", "issue new currency to stop hyperinflation", "adopt the Dawes plan"], "answer": "sign the Treaty of Versailles" }, { "questionText": "In Germany, the price of a loaf of bread, which had been .13 in 1914, by November 15, 1923 had become", "answers": ["100,000,000,000 marks", "3.50 marks", "700 marks", "2,000,000 marks"], "answer": "100,000,000,000 marks" }, { "questionText": "Gleichschaltung:", "answers": ["thought control, molding society to a single worldview", "replacing one currency with another", "a method of lightning warfare by land, sea, and air", "Marxism with racial struggle replacing class struggle"], "answer": "thought control, molding society to a single worldview" }, { "questionText": "The goal of the State, according to Hitler:", "answers": ["conservation of the racial characteristics of mankind", "resolution of the class struggle", "perfect coordination, as in a beehive", "guaranteeing rights to a certain standard of living"], "answer": "conservation of the racial characteristics of mankind" }, { "questionText": "The idealist's central argument against realism: that realism inevitably leads to", "answers": ["skepticism", "relativism", "totalitarianism", "socialism"], "answer": "skepticism" }, { "questionText": "That the world might be different, even though all our perceptions and thoughts of it might be the same, has been taken to show that", "answers": ["knowledge is impossible", "there are mind-independent objects", "truth is the limit of all possible perspectives", "we must achieve a systematic union of ends"], "answer": "knowledge is impossible" }, { "questionText": "The missing explanation argument: ________ cannot explain ___________.", "answers": ["idealism; regularities in experience", "realism; variations in perception", "fascism; respect for natural rights", "relativism; the difference between belief and knowledge"], "answer": "idealism; regularities in experience" }, { "questionText": "The Nazi Party built its electoral appeal in part by", "answers": ["inciting street violence and blaming it on the opposition", "promising middle-class tax cuts", "denouncing socialism", "promising to abide by the Treaty of Versailles"], "answer": "inciting street violence and blaming it on the opposition" }, { "questionText": "Camus sees it as inevitable that, in our everyday experience, we at some point encounter", "answers": ["the absurd", "reality", "the limits of knowledge", "our true natures"], "answer": "the absurd" }, { "questionText": "Oikophobia is fear or hatred of", "answers": ["one's own", "pigs", "other people", "the absurd"], "answer": "one's own" }, { "questionText": "Heidegger believes we confront an existential problem, because we find ourselves", "answers": ["thrown into a world not of our own making", "forced to conform to society's expectations of us", "the demands of civilization and morality", "self-deceived, hiding from ourselves our true, contradictory nature"], "answer": "thrown into a world not of our own making" }, { "questionText": "Existentialists believe that we are radically", "answers": ["free", "self-deceived", "incapable of knowledge", "divided between reason and emotion"], "answer": "free" }, { "questionText": "Camus's response to the existential dilemma:", "answers": ["\"my revolt, my freedom, my passion\"", "\"my acceptance of life as it is and always will be\"", "\"my quest to become who I really am\"", "\"my perpetual; struggle to become what I am not\""], "answer": "\"my revolt, my freedom, my passion\"" }, { "questionText": "The slogan \"existence precedes essence\" defines", "answers": ["existentialism", "idealism", "subjectivism", "noncognitivism"], "answer": "existentialism" }, { "questionText": "Charles Taylor describes us as \"self-interpreting animals,\" a point Sartre makes by saying we have", "answers": ["being for itself", "being in itself", "thrownness", "authenticity"], "answer": "being for itself" }, { "questionText": "Bad faith is the opposite of", "answers": ["authenticity", "self-interpretation", "self-consciousness", "alienation"], "answer": "authenticity" }, { "questionText": "Camus's goal: to live", "answers": ["without appeal", "with a hard, gem-like flame", "unknown", "as an abstract perceiver of the world"], "answer": "without appeal" }, { "questionText": "“I think that if I give him everything I possibly can and ask nothing from him in return, noblesse oblige, he won’t try to annex anything and will work with me for a world of democracy and peace,” Franklin Delano Roosevelt said of", "answers": ["Stalin", "Churchill", "Hitler", "Mussolini"], "answer": "Stalin" }, { "questionText": "The line dividing the free countries of Western Europe from those under Soviet domination after World War II:", "answers": ["the Iron Curtain", "the thin red line", "the Maginot Line", "the Siegfried Line"], "answer": "the Iron Curtain" }, { "questionText": "An articulation of ________: “to support free peoples who are resisting attempted subjugation by armed minorities or outside pressure... we must assist free people to work out their own destinies in their own way.”", "answers": ["the Truman Doctrine", "existentialism", "the Marshall Plan", "the Eisenhower Doctrine"], "answer": "the Truman Doctrine" }, { "questionText": "“A long-term, patient but firm and vigilant containment of Russian expansive tendencies” together with “the adroit and vigilant application of counterforce at a series of constantly shifting geographical and political points”:", "answers": ["containment", "expansionism", "confrontation", "detente"], "answer": "containment" }, { "questionText": "Western civilization, Hayek argues, is built on", "answers": ["respect for the individual person qua person", "the pursuit of happiness", "the exploitation of the proletariat", "conscious direction of social forces"], "answer": "respect for the individual person qua person" }, { "questionText": "Pluralism: the view that", "answers": ["goods differ in kind", "truth is subjective", "ethical statements are expressions of emotion", "societies differ in ethical beliefs"], "answer": "goods differ in kind" }, { "questionText": "The terms 'common good' and 'general welfare' have no definite meaning, Hayek argues, because", "answers": ["there is no complete scale of values", "we must live without appeal", "we cannot know the law of nature", "human nature is a mysterious multiplicity"], "answer": "there is no complete scale of values" }, { "questionText": "The problem of distributed knowledge:", "answers": ["markets contain vast amounts of information that no one person or group can possess", "markets sometimes fail to produce the best outcome", "markets always produce the best possible outcome", "knowledge satisfies laws of distribution"], "answer": "markets contain vast amounts of information that no one person or group can possess" }, { "questionText": "The tragedy of the commons arises because", "answers": ["what makes sense for each might not make sense for all", "politics tends toward the least common denominator", "life is tragic, ending in death", "people choose ends unwisely"], "answer": "what makes sense for each might not make sense for all" }, { "questionText": "Lord Acton: \"Power tends to corrupt, and", "answers": ["absolute power corrupts absolutely.\"", "ambition leads to power.\"", "corruption destroys the social contract.\"", "political power tends to destroy.\""], "answer": "absolute power corrupts absolutely.\"" }, { "questionText": "Plato's story of the ring of Gyges suggests that, if you could get away with anything, you would probably", "answers": ["act unethically", "do the right thing anyway", "act foolishly", "become virtuous"], "answer": "act unethically" }, { "questionText": "Socialism, Hayek argues, tends to treat people as", "answers": ["means to an end", "ends in themselves", "citizens rather than subjects", "having rights and liberties"], "answer": "means to an end" }, { "questionText": "In Hayek's view, \"the most powerful monopolist conceivable\":", "answers": ["government", "the corporation", "private property", "the Party"], "answer": "government" }, { "questionText": "Noncognitivism in ethics holds that saying 'Murder is wrong' amounts to saying", "answers": ["\"Murder: Boo!\"", "\"I disapprove of murder.\"", "\"We disapprove of murder.\"", "\"Murder merits disapproval.\""], "answer": "\"Murder: Boo!\"" }, { "questionText": "In ethics, C. S. Lewis is best described as", "answers": ["a natural law theorist", "a subjectivist", "a noncognitivist", "an emotivist"], "answer": "a natural law theorist" }, { "questionText": "Augustine speaks of the goal of moral education as ordo amoris, the order of loves (or affections), meaning that we must learn to", "answers": ["make our feelings congruent with the circumstances giving rise to them", "love others as well as ourselves", "align our affections with our society's norms", "live passionately, without appeal"], "answer": "make our feelings congruent with the circumstances giving rise to them" }, { "questionText": "The view that normative statements are not truth-apt:", "answers": ["noncognitivism", "subjectivism", "natural law theory", "idealism"], "answer": "noncognitivism" }, { "questionText": "The view that 'murder is wrong' is equivalent to 'I (or we) disapprove of murder' is", "answers": ["subjectivism", "noncognitivism", "idealism", "natural law theory"], "answer": "subjectivism" }, { "questionText": "`Kindness is a virtue' is equivalent to 'Kindness merits approval,' according to", "answers": ["natural law theory", "subjectivism", "noncognitivism", "existentialism"], "answer": "natural law theory" }, { "questionText": "Plato's three parts of the soul:", "answers": ["reason, emotion, desire", "id, ego, superego", "spirit, flesh, reason", "conscious, subconscious, preconscious"], "answer": "reason, emotion, desire" }, { "questionText": "In Plato's image of the soul as a chariot, the driver is", "answers": ["the rational element", "the spirited element", "the appetitive element", "the material element"], "answer": "the rational element" }, { "questionText": "The paradox of subjectivism: the subjectivist understands norms as signaling approval of virtues while", "answers": ["undercutting those same virtues", "assuming that they merit approval", "denying that any virtues exist", "assuming that virtues are mind-independent"], "answer": "undercutting those same virtues" }, { "questionText": "Ferlinghetti, in writing \"I am waiting for the final withering away of all governments,\"", "answers": ["alludes to Marx's vision of a communist society", "advocates top-down conceptions of government", "allies himself with McCarthyism", "advocates Kennedy's vision of a new role for America in the world"], "answer": "alludes to Marx's vision of a communist society" }, { "questionText": "Ferlinghetti's reference to \"intimations of immortality,\" \"recollecting my early childhood,\" and \"the fleeing lovers on the Grecian Urn\" place his poem within the tradition of", "answers": ["Romanticism", "Realism", "Surrealism", "Dada"], "answer": "Romanticism" }, { "questionText": "The doctrine that the United States would have to apply occasional counterforce to attempts at Communist expansion:", "answers": ["containment", "the New Frontier", "the Great Society", "detente"], "answer": "containment" }, { "questionText": "“Let every nation know, whether it wishes us well or ill, that we shall pay any price, bear any burden, meet any hardship, support any friend, oppose any foe, to ensure the survival and success of liberty.” This expresses the foreign policy doctrine of", "answers": ["John F. Kennedy", "John Quincy Adams", "Harry Truman", "Dwight D. Eisenhower"], "answer": "John F. Kennedy" }, { "questionText": "In response to discovering missile bases under construction in Cuba, President Kennedy decided to", "answers": ["impose a naval blockade", "invade the island", "apply diplomatic pressure", "attack the bases by air"], "answer": "impose a naval blockade" }, { "questionText": "Federal government spending, as a proportion of the economy, has risen from a historical base of around 3% from 1790 to 1914 to around _____ today.", "answers": ["24%", "10%", "60%", "45%"], "answer": "24%" }, { "questionText": "Part of President Johnson's Great Society program:", "answers": ["Medicare", "the Social Security system", "the Agricultural Adjustment Act", "the income tax"], "answer": "Medicare" }, { "questionText": "The view that government authority is justified if people would, under ideal circumstances, agree to live under it:", "answers": ["social contract theory", "utilitarianism", "entitlement theory", "progressivism"], "answer": "social contract theory" }, { "questionText": "Every social contract theory must specify ideal circumstances of choice. Rawls's conception of those ideal circumstances is the", "answers": ["original position", "difference principle", "reflective equilibrium", "equal opportunity principle"], "answer": "original position" }, { "questionText": "Rawls's veil of ignorance: those choosing principles of justice in an ideal circumstance should NOT know", "answers": ["their natural abilities, propensities, or conception of the good", "relevant facts about economics, society, and politics", "what authority they would not would not grant to government", "whether everyone would benefit from the arrangement"], "answer": "their natural abilities, propensities, or conception of the good" }, { "questionText": "Rawls's first principle:", "answers": ["Each should have an equal right to the most extensive basic liberties compatible with similar liberties for others", "inqualities should be arranged to be to everyone's advantage", "inequalities must be attached to positions and offices open to all", "everyone must benefit from the arrangement of social institutions"], "answer": "Each should have an equal right to the most extensive basic liberties compatible with similar liberties for others" }, { "questionText": "A distributive injustice, according to Rawls:", "answers": ["an inequality that harms the least advantaged", "an inequality that does not contribute to higher overall welfare", "an inequality greater than might be found in another institutional arrangement", "a level of well-being lower than some minimal standard"], "answer": "an inequality that harms the least advantaged" }, { "questionText": "“a set of critical, strategic and rhetorical practices employing concepts such as difference, repetition, the trace, the simulacrum, and hyperreality to destabilize other concepts such as presence, identity, historical progress, epistemic certainty, and the univocity of meaning”:", "answers": ["postmodernism", "structuralism", "Marxism", "progressivism"], "answer": "postmodernism" }, { "questionText": "“the belief that phenomena of human life are not intelligible except through their interrelations\":", "answers": ["structuralism", "postmodernism", "progressivism", "existentialism"], "answer": "structuralism" }, { "questionText": "Lyotard's definition of postmodernism:", "answers": ["incredulity toward metanarratives", "weird for the sake of weird", "the view that behind local variations in the surface phenomena there are constant laws of abstract culture", "the view that there are different language games"], "answer": "incredulity toward metanarratives" }, { "questionText": "Lyotard distinguishes knowledge from learning, for it includes more, for example,", "answers": ["competences, knowing how to....", "statements that can be true or false", "procedures of proof and hypothesis testing", "multiple criteria of truth"], "answer": "competences, knowing how to...." }, { "questionText": "Immediacy (the myth of the given):", "answers": ["language or thought can relate to the world directly", "the structure of language matches the structure of thought", "all knowledge is immediate, perceived rather than inferred", "the structure of thought matches the structure of the world"], "answer": "language or thought can relate to the world directly" }, { "questionText": "Hegel's attack on the myth of the given undercuts the distinction between", "answers": ["perceiving and conceiving", "thinking and doing", "thinking and saying", "knowing and believing"], "answer": "perceiving and conceiving" }, { "questionText": "Descartes: things I cannot doubt—", "answers": ["I am, I think", "I feel, I suffer", "I believe, I know", "I doubt, I wonder"], "answer": "I am, I think" }, { "questionText": "Descartes: I am, essentially,", "answers": ["a thing that thinks", "a human being", "a mind in a body", "an agent with moral responsibility"], "answer": "a thing that thinks" }, { "questionText": "\"A practice is just if it is in accordance with the principles which all who participate in it might reasonably be expected to propose or to acknowledge before one another when they are similarly circumstanced and required to make a firm commitment in advance without knowledge of what will be their peculiar condition....\"", "answers": ["Rawls", "Kennedy", "Roosevelt", "Nozick"], "answer": "Rawls" }, { "questionText": "We are, Didion writes,", "answers": ["what we learned as children", "what we eat", "what we will become", "what we are not"], "answer": "what we learned as children" }, { "questionText": "Didion is suspicious of any morality that does not relate to", "answers": ["survival", "the ideal good", "virtue", "happiness"], "answer": "survival" }, { "questionText": "\"Don't let your conscience be your guide,\" Ellis Nelson wrote, agreeing with", "answers": ["Didion", "Lewis", "Hume", "Auden"], "answer": "Didion" }, { "questionText": "The U. S. economy in the late 1970s was characterized by", "answers": ["\"stagflation\": stagnation plus inflation", "rapid growth and low unemployment", "low interest rates and a booming stock market", "low energy prices"], "answer": "\"stagflation\": stagnation plus inflation" }, { "questionText": "A theory of distributive justice focusing solely on levels of inequality would be", "answers": ["an end-result theory", "a welfare theory", "a patterned theory", "a historical theory"], "answer": "an end-result theory" }, { "questionText": "A philosopher holding an end-result theory of justice:", "answers": ["Rawls", "Aristotle", "Marx", "Nozick"], "answer": "Rawls" }, { "questionText": "Marx's theory of justice is", "answers": ["patterned", "end-result", "historical", "structural"], "answer": "patterned" }, { "questionText": "A philosopher holding that the justice of a distribution depends on how it came about:", "answers": ["Nozick", "Rawls", "Marx", "Aristotle"], "answer": "Nozick" }, { "questionText": "NOT one of Nozick's principles of justice:", "answers": ["difference", "rectification", "acquisition", "transfer"], "answer": "difference" }, { "questionText": "Nozick argues that only historical theories of justice", "answers": ["respect freedom", "reduce inequality", "meet people's needs", "take merit into account"], "answer": "respect freedom" }, { "questionText": "Hayek's definition of socialism:", "answers": ["centralized conscious direction of social forces to consciously chosen ends", "pursuit of the collective good", "government ownership of the means of production", "dictatorship of the proletariat"], "answer": "centralized conscious direction of social forces to consciously chosen ends" }, { "questionText": "Margaret Thatcher: \"the problem with socialism is that eventually", "answers": ["you run out of other people's money", "your plans do not match reality", "you encounter questions you cannot answer", "people refuse to follow your orders"], "answer": "you run out of other people's money" }, { "questionText": "Ronald Reagan's view of the central political issue:", "answers": ["self-government vs. rule by an elite", "the principal-agent problem", "the distributed knowledge problem", "a crisis of self-confidence"], "answer": "self-government vs. rule by an elite" }, { "questionText": "Reagan: \"the nearest thing to eternal life we'll ever see on this earth\":", "answers": ["a government bureau", "rights to life, liberty, and the pursuit of happiness", "the United States of America", "the U. S. military"], "answer": "a government bureau" }].map(question => {question.mcq = true; return question})
let quoteQuestions = [{"questionText":"\"With all this money around you don’t want to be a fool while everyone else is making.\"","answers":["Bellow","Camus","Didion","Lyotard"],"answer":"Bellow"},{"questionText":"“‘What art thou?’ Nothing. That’s the answer. Nothing. In the heart of hearts—Nothing! So of course you can’t stand that and want to be Something, and you try.”","answers":["Bellow","Camus","Didion","Lewis"],"answer":"Bellow"},{"questionText":"\"Who is a visionary sort of animal. Who has to believe that he can know why he exists. Though he has never seriously tried to find out why.\"","answers":["Bellow","Nozick","Havel","Borges"],"answer":"Bellow"},{"questionText":"\"For that is the truth of it—that we all know, God, that we know, that we know, we know, we know.”","answers":["Bellow","Camus","Churchill","Solzhenitsyn"],"answer":"Bellow"},{"questionText":"\"any science that legitimates itself with reference to a metadiscourse of this kind making explicit appeal to some grand narrative.\"","answers":["Lyotard","Havel","Lewis","Camus"],"answer":"Lyotard"},{"questionText":"\"[He] was assigned to be carrier of a load which was his own self.\"","answers":["Bellow","Lewis","Camus","Sontag"],"answer":"Bellow"},{"questionText":"\"The Sermon on the Mount is the last word in Christian ethics. Everyone respects the Quakers. Still, it is not on these terms that Ministers assume their responsibilities of guiding states.\"","answers":["Churchill","Lewis","Rawls","Nozick"],"answer":"Churchill"},{"questionText":"\"Those who are prone by temperament and character to seek sharp and clear-cut solutions of difficult and obscure problems, who are ready to fight when- ever some challenge comes from a foreign Power, have not always been right.\"","answers":["Churchill","Rawls","Nozick","Bellow"],"answer":"Churchill"},{"questionText":"\"No case of this kind can be judged apart from its circumstances. The facts may be unknown at the time, and estimates of them must be largely guesswork, coloured by the general feelings and aims of whoever is trying to pronounce.\"","answers":["Churchill","Borges","Rawls","Nozick"],"answer":"Churchill"},{"questionText":"\"If it should eventually be accepted as historical truth, it will be another example of the very small accidents upon which the fortunes of mankind turn.\"","answers":["Churchill","Lewis","Nozick","Havel"],"answer":"Churchill"},{"questionText":"\"The belief that security can be obtained by throwing a small state to the wolves is a fatal delusion.\"","answers":["Churchill","Borges","Didion","Lewis"],"answer":"Churchill"},{"questionText":"\"...the same referent cannot supply a plurality of contradictory or inconsistent proofs. Or stated differently: ‘God’ is not deceptive.”","answers":["Lyotard","Camus","Lewis","Didion"],"answer":"Lyotard"},{"questionText":"“There are many different language games—a heterogeneity of elements. They only give rise to institutions in patches—local determinism.”","answers":["Lyotard","Camus","Didion","Lewis"],"answer":"Lyotard"},{"questionText":"\"I define postmodern as incredulity toward metanarratives\"","answers":["Lyotard","Camus","Lewis","Didion"],"answer":"Lyotard"},{"questionText":"\"Their duty is first so to deal with other nations as to avoid strife and war and to eschew aggression in all its forms, whether for nationalistic or ideological objects. But the safety of the State, the lives and freedom of their own fellow country-men, to whom they owe their position, make it right and imperative in the last resort, or when a final and definite conviction has been reached, that the use of force should not be excluded.\"","answers":["Churchill","Havel","Lewis","Didion"],"answer":"Churchill"},{"questionText":"\"These are the dilemmas upon which mankind has throughout its history been so frequently impaled. Final judgment upon them can only be recorded by history in relation to the facts of the case as known to the parties at the time, and also as subsequently proved.\"","answers":["Churchill","Didion","Lewis","Nozick"],"answer":"Churchill"},{"questionText":"\"There is, however, one helpful guide, namely, for a nation to keep its word and to act in accordance with its treaty obligations to allies. This guide is called honour.\"","answers":["Churchill","Borges","Camus","Sontag"],"answer":"Churchill"},{"questionText":"\"Today everything exists to end in a photograph.\"","answers":["Sontag","Camus","Lyotard","Borges"],"answer":"Sontag"},{"questionText":"\"It is baffling to reflect that what men call honour does not correspond always to Christian ethics.\"","answers":["Churchill","Borges","Nozick","Lyotard"],"answer":"Churchill"},{"questionText":"\"Reality has always been interpreted through the reports given by images; and philosophers since Plato have tried to loosen our dependence on images by evoking the standard of an image-free way of apprehending the real.\"","answers":["Sontag","Borges","Lyotard","Churchill"],"answer":"Sontag"},{"questionText":"\"Honour is often influenced by that element of pride which plays so large a part in its inspiration. An exaggerated code of honour leading to the performance of utterly vain and unreasonable deeds could not be defended, however fine it might look. Here, however, the moment came when Honour pointed the path of Duty, and when also the right judgment of the facts at that time would have reinforced its dictates.\"","answers":["Churchill","Lewis","Camus","Hayek"],"answer":"Churchill"},{"questionText":"\"Cameras implement an aesthetic view of reality by being a machine-toy that extends to everyone the possibility of making disinterested judgments about importance, interest, beauty. (“That would make a good picture.”)\"","answers":["Sontag","Lyotard","Camus","Hayek"],"answer":"Sontag"},{"questionText":"\"Moreover, this had been a war, not of governments, but of peoples. The whole life-energy of the greatest nations had been poured out in wrath and slaughter.\"","answers":["Churchill","Borges","Sontag","Camus"],"answer":"Churchill"},{"questionText":"\"Any photograph has multiple meanings.\"","answers":["Sontag","Lyotard","Camus","Borges"],"answer":"Sontag"},{"questionText":"\"No one in great authority had the wit, ascendancy, or detachment from public folly to declare these fundamental, brutal facts to the electorates; nor would anyone have been believed if he had.\"","answers":["Churchill","Camus","Lyotard","Hayek"],"answer":"Churchill"},{"questionText":"\"The camera makes reality atomic, manageable, and opaque. It is a view of the world which denies interconnectedness, continuity, but which confers on each moment the character of a mystery.\"","answers":["Sontag","Lyotard","Camus","Borges"],"answer":"Sontag"},{"questionText":"\"Al this is a sad story of complicated idiocy in the making of which much toil and virtue was consumed.\"","answers":["Churchill","Sontag","Lewis","Camus"],"answer":"Churchill"},{"questionText":"\"everybody seemed pleased and appeared to think this might go on forever. History will characterise all these transactions as insane.\"","answers":["Churchill","Nozick","Hayek","Rawls"],"answer":"Churchill"},{"questionText":"\"The crimes of the vanquished find their background and their explanation, though not, of course, their pardon, in the follies of the victors. Without these follies crime would have found neither tempta- tion nor opportunity.\"","answers":["Churchill","Solzhenitsyn","Rawls","Nozick"],"answer":"Churchill"},{"questionText":"\"Like a pair of binoculars with no right or wrong end, the camera makes exotic things near, intimate; and familiar things small, abstract, strange, much farther away.\"","answers":["Sontag","Lyotard","Hayek","Camus"],"answer":"Sontag"},{"questionText":"“photography implies instant access to the real.”","answers":["Sontag","Borges","Lewis","Lyotard"],"answer":"Sontag"},{"questionText":"\"We have at length emerged from a scene of material ruin and moral havoc the like of which had never darkened the imagination of former centuries.\"","answers":["Churchill","Borges","Camus","Didion"],"answer":"Churchill"},{"questionText":"\"To collect photographs is to collect the world.\"","answers":["Sontag","Borges","Lewis","Bellow"],"answer":"Sontag"},{"questionText":"\"Humankind lingers unregenerately in Plato’s cave, still reveling, its age-old habit, in mere images of the truth.\"","answers":["Sontag","Churchill","Havel","Lyotard"],"answer":"Sontag"},{"questionText":"\"We shall see how the counsels of prudence and restraint may become the prime agents of mortal danger; how the middle course adopted from desires for safety and a quiet life may be found to lead direct to the bull's-eye of disaster. We shall see how absolute is the need of a broad path of international action pursued by many states in common across the years, irrespective of the ebb and flow of national politics.\"","answers":["Churchill","Borges","Rawls","Nozick"],"answer":"Churchill"},{"questionText":"\"In contrast to the amorous relation, which is based on how something looks, understanding is based on how it functions. And functioning takes place in time, and must be explained in time. Only that which narrates can make us understand.\"","answers":["Sontag","Hayek","Solzhenitsyn","Churchill"],"answer":"Sontag"},{"questionText":"\"Photography is an elegiac art, a twilight art.\"","answers":["Sontag","Lyotard","Churchill","Camus"],"answer":"Sontag"},{"questionText":"\"Industrial societies turn their citizens into image-junkies; it is the most irresistible form of mental pollution.\"","answers":["Sontag","Borges","Lyotard","Camus"],"answer":"Sontag"},{"questionText":"\"Although there is a sense in which the camera does indeed capture reality, not just interpret it, photographs are as much an interpretation of the world as paintings and drawings are.\"","answers":["Sontag","Lewis","Hayek","Lyotard"],"answer":"Sontag"},{"questionText":"\"The camera makes everyone a tourist in other people’s reality, and eventually in one’s own.\"","answers":["Sontag","Camus","Lyotard","Churchill"],"answer":"Sontag"},{"questionText":"\"The nations of this planet are congenitally idealist. Their language and the derivations of their language - religion, letters, metaphysics - all presuppose idealism. The world for them is not a concourse of objects in space; it is a heterogeneous series of independent acts.\"","answers":["Borges","Camus","Lewis","Bellow"],"answer":"Borges"},{"questionText":"\"Hume noted for all time that Berkeley's arguments did not admit the slightest refutation nor did they cause the slightest conviction.\"","answers":["Borges","Camus","Churchill","Lyotard"],"answer":"Borges"},{"questionText":"\"It is no exaggeration to state that the classic culture of Tlön comprises only one discipline: psychology. All others are subordinated to it.\"","answers":["Borges","Lyotard","Didion","Lewis"],"answer":"Borges"},{"questionText":"\"...the men of this planet conceive the universe as a series of mental processes which do not develop in space but successively in time.\"","answers":["Borges","Bellow","Lewis","Churchill"],"answer":"Borges"},{"questionText":"\"Every mental state is irreducible: there mere fact of naming it—i.e., of classifying it—implies a falsification.\"","answers":["Borges","Sontag","Lyotard","Camus"],"answer":"Borges"},{"questionText":"\"The metaphysicians ... do not seek for the truth or even for verisimilitude, but rather for the astounding. They judge that metaphysics is a branch of fantastic literature.\"","answers":["Borges","Lewis","Lyotard","Didion"],"answer":"Borges"},{"questionText":"\"The heresiarch would deduce from this story the reality - i.e., the continuity - of the nine coins which were recovered. It is absurd (he affirmed) to imagine that four of the coins have not existed between Tuesday and Thursday, three between Tuesday and Friday afternoon, two between Tuesday and Friday morning.\"","answers":["Borges","Solzhenitsyn","Hayek","Churchill"],"answer":"Borges"},{"questionText":"\"...a kind of reductio ad absurdum: the hypothetical case of nine men who on nine nights suffer a severe pain. Would it not be ridiculous - they questioned - to pretend that this pain is one and the same?\"","answers":["Borges","Camus","Didion","Bellow"],"answer":"Borges"},{"questionText":"\"Centuries and centuries of idealism have not failed to influence reality.\"","answers":["Borges","Havel","Lewis","Camus"],"answer":"Borges"},{"questionText":"\"Things became duplicated...; they also tend to become effaced and lose their details when they are forgotten. A classic example is the doorway which survived so long it was visited by a beggar and disappeared at his death. At times some birds, a horse, have saved the ruins of an amphitheater.\"","answers":["Borges","Solzhenitsyn","Camus","Hayek"],"answer":"Borges"},{"questionText":"\"Almost immediately, reality yielded on more than one account. The truth is that it longed to yield.\"","answers":["Borges","Bellow","Solzhenitsyn","Churchill"],"answer":"Borges"},{"questionText":"\"How could one do other than submit to Tlön, to the minute and vast evidence of an orderly planet?\"","answers":["Borges","Lewis","Camus","Nozick"],"answer":"Borges"},{"questionText":"\"It is useless to answer that reality is also orderly. Perhaps it is, but in accordance with divine laws—I translate: inhuman laws—which we never quite grasp.\"","answers":["Borges","Camus","Lewis","Havel"],"answer":"Borges"},{"questionText":"\"Tlön is surely a labyrinth, but it is a labyrinth devised by men, a labyrinth destined to be deciphered by men.\"","answers":["Borges","Rawls","Camus","Bellow"],"answer":"Borges"},{"questionText":"\"Enchanted by its rigor, humanity forgets over and again that it is a rigor of chess masters, not of angels.\"","answers":["Borges","Solzhenitsyn","Camus","Lewis"],"answer":"Borges"},{"questionText":"\"Already the schools have been invaded by the (conjectural) \"primitive language\"...; already the teaching of its harmonious history (filled with moving episodes) has wiped out the one which governed in my childhood; already a fictitious past occupies in our memories the place of another, a past of which we know nothing with certainty - not even a that it is false.\"","answers":["Borges","Lewis","Camus","Churchill"],"answer":"Borges"},{"questionText":"“I draw from the absurd three consequences, which are my revolt, my freedom, and my passion.”","answers":["Camus","Borges","Lewis","Bellow"],"answer":"Camus"},{"questionText":"\"Judging whether life is or is not worth living amounts to answering the fundamental question of philosophy.\"","answers":["Camus","Lewis","Borges","Bellow"],"answer":"Camus"},{"questionText":"\"...the meaning of life is the most urgent of questions.\"","answers":["Camus","Borges","Bellow","Lewis"],"answer":"Camus"},{"questionText":"\"...in a universe suddenly divested of illusions and lights, man feels an alien, a stranger.\"","answers":["Camus","Borges","Bellow","Lewis"],"answer":"Camus"},{"questionText":"\"This divorce between man and this life, the actor and his setting, is properly the feeling of absurdity.\"","answers":["Camus","Borges","Bellow","Lewis"],"answer":"Camus"},{"questionText":"\"It is always easy to be logical. It is almost impossible to be logical to the bitter end.\"","answers":["Camus","Borges","Bellow","Lewis"],"answer":"Camus"},{"questionText":"\"At any street corner the feeling of absurdity can strike any man in the face.\"","answers":["Camus","Bellow","Borges","Lewis"],"answer":"Camus"},{"questionText":"\"No code of ethics and no effort are justifiable a priori in the face of the cruel mathematics that command our condition.\"","answers":["Camus","Bellow","Borges","Lewis"],"answer":"Camus"},{"questionText":"\"I don’t know whether this world has a meaning that transcends it. But I know that I do not know that meaning and that it is impossible for me just now to know it.\"","answers":["Camus","Bellow","Borges","Lewis"],"answer":"Camus"},{"questionText":"\"Knowing whether or not one can live without appeal is all that interests me.\"","answers":["Camus","Borges","Bellow","Lewis"],"answer":"Camus"},{"questionText":"\"The preceding merely defines a way of thinking. But the point is to live.\"","answers":["Camus","Lewis","Bellow","Borges"],"answer":"Camus"},{"questionText":"\"Socialism means slavery.\"","answers":["Hayek","Camus","Lewis","Churchill"],"answer":"Hayek"},{"questionText":"\"‘Common good,’ ‘general welfare’ “have no sufficiently definite meaning to determine a particular course of action.”","answers":["Hayek","Hume","Camus","Lewis"],"answer":"Hayek"},{"questionText":"\"The curious task of economics is to demonstrate to men how little they really know about what they imagine they can design.\"","answers":["Hayek","Havel","Nozick","Rawls"],"answer":"Hayek"},{"questionText":"“Socialism can be put into practice only by methods which most socialists disapprove.”","answers":["Hayek","Borges","Rawls","Lyotard"],"answer":"Hayek"},{"questionText":"“There are strong reasons for believing that what to us appear the worst features of totalitarian systems are not accidental byproducts but phenomena which totalitarianism is certain to sooner or later produce.”","answers":["Hayek","Sontag","Rawls","Churchill"],"answer":"Hayek"},{"questionText":"“The practice of socialism is everywhere totalitarian.”","answers":["Hayek","Churchill","Lewis","Didion"],"answer":"Hayek"},{"questionText":"“... the unscrupulous and uninhibited are likely to be more ‘successful’ in a society tending toward totalitarianism.”","answers":["Hayek","Sontag","Nozick","Rawls"],"answer":"Hayek"},{"questionText":"“The \"ethics\" produced by collectivism will be altogether different from moral notions that have led to the demand for collectivism.”","answers":["Hayek","Bellow","Lewis","Didion"],"answer":"Hayek"},{"questionText":"“Once you admit that the individual is merely a means to serve the ends of the higher entity called society or the nation, most of those features of totalitarian regimes which horrify us follow of necessity.”","answers":["Hayek","Didion","Lyotard","Churchill"],"answer":"Hayek"},{"questionText":"“And as there will be need for actions which are bad in themselves, and which all those still influenced by traditional morals will be reluctant to perform, the readiness to do bad things becomes a path to promotion and power.”","answers":["Hayek","Camus","Borges","Churchill"],"answer":"Hayek"},{"questionText":"“Although the professed aim of planning would be that man should cease to be a mere means, in fact—since it would be impossible to take account in the plan of individual likes and dislikes—the individual would more than ever become a mere means, to be used by the authority in the service of such abstractions as the ‘social welfare’ or ‘the good of the community.’”","answers":["Hayek","Didion","Nozick","Borges"],"answer":"Hayek"},{"questionText":"“The more the state ‘plans,’ the more difficult planning becomes for the individual.”","answers":["Hayek","Camus","Bellow","Solzhenitsyn"],"answer":"Hayek"},{"questionText":"“To produce the same result for different people, it is necessary to treat them differently.”","answers":["Hayek","Lewis","Lyotard","Rawls"],"answer":"Hayek"},{"questionText":"“The tragedy of collectivist thought is that, while it starts out to make reason supreme, it ends by destroying reason because it misconceives the process on which reason depends.”","answers":["Hayek","Rawls","Churchill","Camus"],"answer":"Hayek"},{"questionText":"\"They know the Law of Nature; they break it.\"","answers":["Lewis","Borges","Camus","Bellow"],"answer":"Lewis"},{"questionText":"\"...human beings, all over the earth, have this curious idea that they ought to behave in a certain way, and cannot really get rid of it.\"","answers":["Lewis","Bellow","Camus","Borges"],"answer":"Lewis"},{"questionText":"\"For every one pupil who needs to be guarded from a weak excess of sensibility there are three who need to be awakened from the slumber of cold vulgarity.\"","answers":["Lewis","Camus","Borges","Bellow"],"answer":"Lewis"},{"questionText":"\"The task of the modern educator is not to cut down jungles but to irrigate deserts.\"","answers":["Lewis","Bellow","Borges","Camus"],"answer":"Lewis"},{"questionText":"\"The right defence against false sentiments is to inculcate just sentiments.\"","answers":["Lewis","Borges","Camus","Bellow"],"answer":"Lewis"},{"questionText":"“Until quite modern times all teachers and even all men believed the universe to be such that certain emotional reactions on our part could be either congruous or incongruous to it — believed, in fact, that objects did not merely receive, but could merit, our approval or disapproval, our reverence or our contempt.”","answers":["Lewis","Borges","Bellow","Camus"],"answer":"Lewis"},{"questionText":"“St Augustine defines virtue as ordo amoris, the ordinate condition of the affections in which every object is accorded that kind of degree of love which is appropriate to it.”","answers":["Lewis","Borges","Bellow","Camus"],"answer":"Lewis"},{"questionText":"“Aristotle says that the aim of education is to make the pupil like and dislike what he ought.”","answers":["Lewis","Borges","Bellow","Camus"],"answer":"Lewis"},{"questionText":"\"The head rules the belly through the chest.\"","answers":["Lewis","Camus","Bellow","Borges"],"answer":"Lewis"},{"questionText":"“And all the time — such is the tragi-comedy of our situation — we continue to clamour for those very qualities we are rendering impossible.”","answers":["Lewis","Borges","Camus","Bellow"],"answer":"Lewis"},{"questionText":"“In a sort of ghastly simplicity we remove the organ and demand the function. We make men without chests and expect of them virtue and enterprise. We laugh at honour and are shocked to find traitors in our midst. We castrate and bid the geldings be fruitful.”","answers":["Lewis","Borges","Bellow","Camus"],"answer":"Lewis"},{"questionText":"\"He loved them. They were his brothers and his sisters. He was imperfect and disfigured himself, but what difference did that make if he was united with them by this blaze of love? And as he walked he began to say, \"Oh my brothers--my brothers and my sisters,\" blessing them all as well as himself.\"","answers":["Bellow","Havel","Lewis","Borges"],"answer":"Bellow"},{"questionText":"\"And say to yourself here-and-now, here-and-now, here-and-now.\"","answers":["Bellow","Camus","Borges","Lewis"],"answer":"Bellow"},{"questionText":"\"Be in the present. Grasp the hour, the moment, the instant.\"","answers":["Bellow","Camus","Lyotard","Lewis"],"answer":"Bellow"},{"questionText":"\"I don't know how many times you have to be burned in order to learn something. The same mistakes, over and over.\"","answers":["Bellow","Camus","Solzhenitsyn","Borges"],"answer":"Bellow"},{"questionText":"\"He heard it and sank deeper than sorrow, through torn sobs and cries toward the consummation of his heart's ultimate need.\"","answers":["Bellow","Camus","Borges","Lewis"],"answer":"Bellow"},{"questionText":"\"In here, the human bosom—mine, yours, everybody's—there isn't just one soul. There's a lot of souls.\"","answers":["Bellow","Borges","Lewis","Camus"],"answer":"Bellow"},{"questionText":"\"Every man realizes that he has to love something or somebody. He feels that he must go outward.\"","answers":["Bellow","Borges","Camus","Havel"],"answer":"Bellow"},{"questionText":"“'If thou canst not love, what art thou?' Are you with me?”","answers":["Bellow","Borges","Camus","Lewis"],"answer":"Bellow"},{"questionText":"“A man is only as good as what he loves.”","answers":["Bellow","Borges","Lewis","Camus"],"answer":"Bellow"},{"questionText":"\"Nature only knows one thing, and that's the present. Present, present, eternal present, like a big, huge, giant wave—colossal, bright and beautiful, full of life and death, climbing into the sky, standing in the seas.\"","answers":["Bellow","Borges","Lewis","Camus"],"answer":"Bellow"},{"questionText":"\"You must go along with the actual, the Here-and-Now, the glory....\"","answers":["Bellow","Borges","Camus","Lewis"],"answer":"Bellow"},{"questionText":"\"In any moment of quiet, when sheer fatigue prevented him from struggling, he was apt to feel this mysterious weight, this growth or collection of nameless things which it was the business of his life to carry about. That must be what a man was for.\"","answers":["Bellow","Borges","Camus","Lewis"],"answer":"Bellow"},{"questionText":"“I think a person finally emerges from all this nonsense when he becomes aware that his life has a much larger meaning he has been ignoring—a transcendent meaning. And that his life is, at its most serious, some kind of religious enterprise, not one that has to do with the hurly-burly of existence.”","answers":["Bellow","Borges","Churchill","Camus"],"answer":"Bellow"},{"questionText":"\"...the great, great crowd, the inexhaustible current of millions of every race and kind pouring out, pressing around, of every age, of every genius, possessors of every human secret, antique and future, in every face the refinement of one particular essence—I labor, I spend, I strive, I design, I love, I cling, I uphold, I give way, I envy, I long, I scorn, I die, I hide, I want.\"","answers":["Bellow","Borges","Lewis","Solzhenitsyn"],"answer":"Bellow"},{"questionText":"“Still, if you will not fight for the right when you can easily win without bloodshed; if you will not fight when your victory will be sure and not too costly; you may come to the moment when you will have to fight with all the odds against you and only a precarious chance of survival. There may even be a worse case. You may have to fight when there is no hope of victory, because it is better to perish than live as slaves.”","answers":["Churchill","Camus","Lewis","Didion"],"answer":"Churchill"},{"questionText":"“If the circumstances are such as to warrant it, force may be used. And if this be so, it should be used under the conditions which are most favourable. There is no merit in putting off a war for a year if, when it comes, it is a far worse war or one much harder to win.”","answers":["Churchill","Havel","Rawls","Nozick"],"answer":"Churchill"},{"questionText":"“Young or old, man or woman, rich or poor, a person is always located at ‘nodal points’ of specific communication circuits, however tiny these may be.”","answers":["Lyotard","Bellow","Didion","Camus"],"answer":"Lyotard"},{"questionText":"“A self does not amount to much, but no self is an island; each exists in a fabric of relations that is now more complex and mobile than ever before.”","answers":["Lyotard","Didion","Bellow","Camus"],"answer":"Lyotard"},{"questionText":"\"Not: I can prove something because reality is the way I say it is. But: as long as I can produce proof, it is permissible to think that reality is the way I say it is.\"","answers":["Lyotard","Churchill","Solzhenitsyn","Camus"],"answer":"Lyotard"},{"questionText":"\"What I say is true because I prove that it is—but what proof is there that my proof is true?\"","answers":["Lyotard","Hayek","Camus","Didion"],"answer":"Lyotard"},{"questionText":"“Thus the narratives allow the society in which they are told, on the one hand, to define its criteria of competence and, on the other, to evaluate according to those criteria what is performed or can be performed within it.”","answers":["Lyotard","Hayek","Didion","Rawls"],"answer":"Lyotard"},{"questionText":"“But what is meant by the term knowledge is not only a set of denotative statements, far from it. It also includes notions of ‘know-how,’ ‘knowing how to live,’ ‘how to listen,’ etc.”","answers":["Lyotard","Lewis","Rawls","Borges"],"answer":"Lyotard"},{"questionText":"“Knowledge, then, is a question of competence that goes beyond the simple determination and application of the criterion of truth....”","answers":["Lyotard","Bellow","Borges","Rawls"],"answer":"Lyotard"},{"questionText":"“Knowledge in general cannot be reduced to science, nor even to learning.”","answers":["Lyotard","Camus","Lewis","Churchill"],"answer":"Lyotard"},{"questionText":"“Young or old, man or woman, rich or poor, a person is always located at ‘nodal points’ of specific communication circuits, however tiny these may be.”","answers":["Lyotard","Bellow","Churchill","Camus"],"answer":"Lyotard"},{"questionText":"\"For better or worse, we are what we learned as children....\"","answers":["Didion","Camus","Havel","Hayek"],"answer":"Didion"},{"questionText":"\"...they had somewhere abdicated their responsibilities, somehow breached their primary loyalties....\"","answers":["Didion","Camus","Lyotard","Borges"],"answer":"Didion"},{"questionText":"\"...we heard such stories as cautionary tales, and they still suggest the only kind of “morality” that seems to me to have any but the most potentially mendacious meaning.\"","answers":["Didion","Camus","Bellow","Lyotard"],"answer":"Didion"},{"questionText":"\"I am talking, you want to say, about a “morality” so primitive that it scarcely deserves the name, a code that has as its point only survival, not the attainment of the ideal good. Exactly.\"","answers":["Didion","Churchill","Camus","Hayek"],"answer":"Didion"},{"questionText":"\"...it is difficult to believe that “the good” is a knowable quantity.\"","answers":["Didion","Camus","Borges","Havel"],"answer":"Didion"},{"questionText":"\"“I followed my own conscience.” “I did what I thought was right.” How many madmen have said it and meant it? How many murderers?\"","answers":["Didion","Churchill","Borges","Lewis"],"answer":"Didion"},{"questionText":"\"Except on the most primitive level—our loyalties to those we love—what could be more arrogant than to claim the primacy of personal conscience?\"","answers":["Didion","Camus","Lyotard","Solzhenitsyn"],"answer":"Didion"},{"questionText":"\"Of course you will say that I do not have the right, even if I had the power, to inflict that unreasonable conscience upon you; nor do I want you to inflict your conscience, however reasonable, however enlightened, upon me.\"","answers":["Didion","Bellow","Borges","Rawls"],"answer":"Didion"},{"questionText":"\"...the ethic of conscience is intrinsically insidious....\"","answers":["Didion","Lewis","Churchill","Havel"],"answer":"Didion"},{"questionText":"\"You see I want to be quite obstinate about insisting that we have no way of knowing – beyond that fundamental loyalty to the social code – what is “right” and what is “wrong,” what is “good” and what “evil.”\"","answers":["Didion","Churchill","Lewis","Solzhenitsyn"],"answer":"Didion"},{"questionText":":...all the ad hoc committees, all the picket lines, all the brave signatures in The New York Times, all the tools of agitprop straight across the spectrum, do not confer upon anyone any ipso facto virtue.\"","answers":["Didion","Churchill","Bellow","Rawls"],"answer":"Didion"},{"questionText":"\"Because when we start deceiving ourselves into thinking not that we want something or need something, not that it is a pragmatic necessity for us to have it, but that it is a moral imperative that we have it, then is when we join the fashionable madmen, and then is when the thin whine of hysteria is heard in the land, and then is when we are in bad trouble. And I suspect we are already there.\"","answers":["Didion","Havel","Hayek","Bellow"],"answer":"Didion"},{"questionText":"\"...innocence ends when one is stripped of the delusion that one likes oneself.\"","answers":["Didion","Hayek","Camus","Bellow"],"answer":"Didion"},{"questionText":"\"Although to be driven back upon oneself is an uneasy affair at best, rather like trying to cross a border with borrowed credentials, it seems to me now the one condition necessary to the beginnings of real self-respect.\"","answers":["Didion","Churchill","Bellow","Lewis"],"answer":"Didion"},{"questionText":"\"...self-deception remains the most difficult deception.\"","answers":["Didion","Havel","Bellow","Nozick"],"answer":"Didion"},{"questionText":"\"The dismal fact is that self-respect has nothing to do with the approval of others....\"","answers":["Didion","Solzhenitsyn","Bellow","Camus"],"answer":"Didion"},{"questionText":"\"However long we postpone it, we eventually lie down alone in that notoriously uncomfortable bed, the one we make ourselves. Whether or not we sleep in it depends, of course, on whether or not we respect ourselves.\"","answers":["Didion","Churchill","Borges","Lyotard"],"answer":"Didion"},{"questionText":"\"In brief, people with self-respect exhibit a certain toughness, a kind of mortal nerve; they display what was once called character....\"","answers":["Didion","Churchill","Bellow","Camus"],"answer":"Didion"},{"questionText":"\"To assign unanswered letters their proper weight, to free us from the expectations of others, to give us back to ourselves – there lies the great, the singular power of self-respect. Without it, one eventually discovers the final turn of the screw: one runs away to find oneself, and finds no one at home.\"","answers":["Didion","Bellow","Havel","Hayek"],"answer":"Didion"},{"questionText":"\"...the fundamental idea in the concept of justice is fairness....\"","answers":["Rawls","Nozick","Didion","Camus"],"answer":"Rawls"},{"questionText":"\"...each person participating in a practice, or affected by it, has an equal right to most extensive liberty compatible with a like liberty for all....\"","answers":["Rawls","Nozick","Hayek","Solzhenitsyn"],"answer":"Rawls"},{"questionText":"\"...inequalities are arbitrary unless it is reasonable to expect that they will work out for everyone's advantage, and provided the positions and offices to which they attach, or from which they may be gained, are open to all.\"","answers":["Rawls","Nozick","Havel","Churchill"],"answer":"Rawls"},{"questionText":"\"There is no reason for circumscribing rights unless their exercise would be incompatible, or would render the practice defining them less effective.\"","answers":["Rawls","Solzhenitsyn","Nozick","Lewis"],"answer":"Rawls"},{"questionText":"\"...an inequality is allowed only if there is reason to believe that the practice with the inequality, or resulting in it, will work for the advantage of every party engaging in it.\"","answers":["Rawls","Nozick","Havel","Hayek"],"answer":"Rawls"},{"questionText":"\"...every party must gain from the inequality.\"","answers":["Rawls","Nozick","Didion","Solzhenitsyn"],"answer":"Rawls"},{"questionText":"\"...it is also necessary that the various offices to which special benefits or burdens attach are open to all.\"","answers":["Rawls","Nozick","Hayek","Havel"],"answer":"Rawls"},{"questionText":"\"But any offices having special benefits must be won in a fair competition in which contestants are judged on their merits.\"","answers":["Rawls","Hayek","Nozick","Sontag"],"answer":"Rawls"},{"questionText":"\"The restrictions which would so arise might be thought of as those a person would keep in mind if he were designing a practice in which his enemy were to assign him his place....\"","answers":["Rawls","Nozick","Sontag","Lyotard"],"answer":"Rawls"},{"questionText":"\"The minimal state is the most extensive state that can be justified. Any state more extensive violates people's rights. \"","answers":["Nozick","Rawls","Hayek","Havel"],"answer":"Nozick"},{"questionText":"\"However, we are not in the position of children who have been given portions of pie by someone who now makes last minute adjustments to rectify careless cutting. There is no central distribution, no person or group entitled to control all the resources, jointly deciding how they are to be doled out.\"","answers":["Nozick","Rawls","Didion","Solzhenitsyn"],"answer":"Nozick"},{"questionText":"\"What each person gets, he gets from others who give to him in exchange for something, or as a gift.\"","answers":["Nozick","Rawls","Havel","Didion"],"answer":"Nozick"},{"questionText":"\"A distribution is just if it arises from another just distribution by legitimate means.\"","answers":["Nozick","Rawls","Hayek","Sontag"],"answer":"Nozick"},{"questionText":"\"The general outlines of the theory of justice in holdings are that the holdings of a person are just if he is entitled to them by the principles of justice in acquisition and transfer, or by the principle of rectification of injustice (as specified by the first two principles).\"","answers":["Nozick","Hayek","Rawls","Churchill"],"answer":"Nozick"},{"questionText":"\"The socialist society would have to forbid capitalist acts between consenting adults.\"","answers":["Nozick","Lyotard","Rawls","Sontag"],"answer":"Nozick"},{"questionText":"\"The Western world has lost its civil courage, both as a whole and separately, in each country, each government, each political party and of course in the United Nations. Such a decline in courage is particularly noticeable among the ruling groups and the intellectual elite, causing an impression of loss of courage by the entire society.\"","answers":["Solzhenitsyn","Hayek","Camus","Churchill"],"answer":"Solzhenitsyn"},{"questionText":"\"Should one point out that from ancient times decline in courage has been considered the beginning of the end?\"","answers":["Solzhenitsyn","Borges","Didion","Lewis"],"answer":"Solzhenitsyn"},{"questionText":"\"Even biology knows that habitual extreme safety and well-being are not advantageous for a living organism.\"","answers":["Solzhenitsyn","Hayek","Lyotard","Camus"],"answer":"Solzhenitsyn"},{"questionText":"\"One almost never sees voluntary self-restraint.\"","answers":["Solzhenitsyn","Camus","Lewis","Didion"],"answer":"Solzhenitsyn"},{"questionText":"\"The defense of individual rights has reached such extremes as to make society as a whole defenseless against certain individuals. It is time, in the West, to defend not so much human rights as human obligations.\"","answers":["Solzhenitsyn","Nozick","Hayek","Camus"],"answer":"Solzhenitsyn"},{"questionText":"\"Destructive and irresponsible freedom has been granted boundless space. Society appears to have little defense against the abyss of human decadence....\"","answers":["Solzhenitsyn","Lyotard","Didion","Rawls"],"answer":"Solzhenitsyn"},{"questionText":"\"Such a tilt of freedom in the direction of evil has come about gradually but it was evidently born primarily out of a humanistic and benevolent concept according to which there is no evil inherent to human nature....\"","answers":["Solzhenitsyn","Rawls","Nozick","Didion"],"answer":"Solzhenitsyn"},{"questionText":"\"Without any censorship, in the West fashionable trends of thought and ideas are carefully separated from those which are not fashionable; nothing is forbidden, but what is not fashionable will hardly ever find its way into periodicals or books or be heard in colleges. Legally your researchers are free, but they are conditioned by the fashion of the day.\"","answers":["Solzhenitsyn","Nozick","Rawls","Churchill"],"answer":"Solzhenitsyn"},{"questionText":"\"Such as it is, however, the press has become the greatest power within the Western countries, more powerful than the legislature, the executive and the judiciary. One would then like to ask: by what law has it been elected and to whom is it responsible?\"","answers":["Solzhenitsyn","Lyotard","Rawls","Borges"],"answer":"Solzhenitsyn"},{"questionText":"\"... the human soul longs for things higher, warmer and purer than those offered by today's mass living habits, introduced by the revolting invasion of publicity, by TV stupor and by intolerable music.\"","answers":["Solzhenitsyn","Lewis","Camus","Nozick"],"answer":"Solzhenitsyn"},{"questionText":"\"... socialism of any type and shade leads to a total destruction of the human spirit and to a leveling of mankind into death.\"","answers":["Solzhenitsyn","Lyotard","Camus","Rawls"],"answer":"Solzhenitsyn"},{"questionText":"\"There are meaningful warnings that history gives a threatened or perishing society. Such are, for instance, the decadence of art, or a lack of great statesmen.\"","answers":["Solzhenitsyn","Didion","Sontag","Borges"],"answer":"Solzhenitsyn"},{"questionText":"\"Very well known [people] say: we cannot apply moral criteria to politics. Thus we mix good and evil, right and wrong and make space for the absolute triumph of absolute Evil in the world. On the contrary, only moral criteria can help the West against communism's well planned world strategy. There are no other criteria.\"","answers":["Solzhenitsyn","Lyotard","Camus","Lewis"],"answer":"Solzhenitsyn"},{"questionText":"\"To defend oneself, one must also be ready to die; there is little such readiness in a society raised in the cult of material well-being.\"","answers":["Solzhenitsyn","Camus","Rawls","Didion"],"answer":"Solzhenitsyn"},{"questionText":"\"We have placed too much hope in political and social reforms, only to find out that we were being deprived of our most precious possession: our spiritual life.\"","answers":["Solzhenitsyn","Hayek","Nozick","Camus"],"answer":"Solzhenitsyn"},{"questionText":"\"If humanism were right in declaring that man is born to be happy, he would not be born to die. Since his body is doomed to die, his task on earth evidently must be of a more spiritual nature. It cannot be unrestrained enjoyment of everyday life. It cannot be the search for the best ways to obtain material goods and then cheerfully get the most out of them. It has to be the fulfillment of a permanent, earnest duty so that one's life journey may become an experience of moral growth, so that one may leave life a better human being than one started it.\"","answers":["Solzhenitsyn","Hayek","Borges","Churchill"],"answer":"Solzhenitsyn"},{"questionText":"\"Only voluntary, inspired self-restraint can raise man above the world stream of materialism.\"","answers":["Solzhenitsyn","Lewis","Camus","Rawls"],"answer":"Solzhenitsyn"},{"questionText":"\"Even if we are spared destruction by war, our lives will have to change if we want to save life from self-destruction. We cannot avoid revising the fundamental definitions of human life and human society. Is it true that man is above everything? Is there no Superior Spirit above him? Is it right that man's life and society's activities have to be determined by material expansion in the first place? Is it permissible to promote such expansion to the detriment of our spiritual integrity?\"","answers":["Solzhenitsyn","Rawls","Nozick","Lyotard"],"answer":"Solzhenitsyn"},{"questionText":"\"The manager of a fruit-and-vegetable shop places in his window, among the onions and carrots, the slogan: \"Workers of the world, unite!\" Why does he do it? What is he trying to communicate to the world? Is he genuinely enthusiastic about the idea of unity among the workers of the world? Is his enthusiasm so great that he feels an irrepressible impulse to acquaint the public with his ideals? Has he really given more than a moment's thought to how such a unification might occur and what it would mean?\"","answers":["Havel","Sontag","Rawls","Nozick"],"answer":"Havel"},{"questionText":"\"Thus the sign helps the greengrocer to conceal from himself the low foundations of his obedience, at the same time concealing the low foundations of power. It hides them behind the facade of something high. And that something is ideology.\"","answers":["Havel","Camus","Borges","Lewis"],"answer":"Havel"},{"questionText":"\"Ideology is a specious way of relating to the world. It offers human beings the illusion of an identity, of dignity, and of morality while making it easier for them to part with them.\"","answers":["Havel","Churchill","Nozick","Rawls"],"answer":"Havel"},{"questionText":"\" As the repository of something suprapersonal and objective, [ideology] enables people to deceive their conscience and conceal their true position and their inglorious modus vivendi, both from the world and from themselves.\"","answers":["Havel","Nozick","Rawls","Lyotard"],"answer":"Havel"},{"questionText":"\"The primary excusatory function of ideology, therefore, is to provide people, both as victims and pillars of the post-totalitarian system, with the illusion that the system is in harmony with the human order and the order of the universe.\"","answers":["Havel","Camus","Borges","Kipling"],"answer":"Havel"},{"questionText":"\"This explains why ideology plays such an important role in the post-totalitarian system: that complex machinery of units, hierarchies, transmission belts, and indirect instruments of manipulation which ensure in countless ways the integrity of the regime, leaving nothing to chance, would be quite simply unthinkable without ideology acting as its all-embracing excuse and as the excuse for each of its parts.\"","answers":["Havel","Thatcher","Truman","Hayek"],"answer":"Havel"},{"questionText":"\"Ideology, in creating a bridge of excuses between the system and the individual, spans the abyss between the aims of the system and the aims of life. It pretends that the requirements of the system derive from the requirements of life. It is a world of appearances trying to pass for reality.\"","answers":["Havel","Rawls","Nozick","Borges"],"answer":"Havel"},{"questionText":"\"Between the aims of the post-totalitarian system and the aims of life there is a yawning abyss: while life, in its essence, moves toward plurality, diversity, independent self-constitution, and self organization, in short, toward the fulfillment of its own freedom, the post-totalitarian system demands conformity, uniformity, and discipline. While life ever strives to create new and improbable structures, the post-totalitarian system contrives to force life into its most probable states.\"","answers":["Havel","Nozick","Rawls","Didion"],"answer":"Havel"},{"questionText":"\"Because the regime is captive to its own lies, it must falsify everything. It falsifies the past. It falsifies the present, and it falsifies the future. It falsifies statistics. It pretends not to possess an omnipotent and unprincipled police apparatus. It pretends to respect human rights. It pretends to persecute no one. It pretends to fear nothing. It pretends to pretend nothing.\"","answers":["Havel","Lewis","Nozick","Camus"],"answer":"Havel"},{"questionText":"\"The post-totalitarian system touches people at every step, but it does so with its ideological gloves on. This is why life in the system is so thoroughly permeated with hypocrisy and lies: government by bureaucracy is called popular government; the working class is enslaved in the name of the working class; the complete degradation of the individual is presented as his ultimate liberation; depriving people of in formation is called making it available; the use of power to manipulate is called the public control of power, and the arbitrary abuse of power is called observing the legal code; the repression of culture is called its development; the expansion of imperial influence is presented as support for the oppressed; the lack of free expression becomes the highest form of freedom; farcical elections become the highest form of democracy; banning independent thought becomes the most scientific of world views; military occupation becomes fraternal assistance.\"","answers":["Havel","Churchill","Lewis","Lyotard"],"answer":"Havel"},{"questionText":"\"Individuals need not believe all these mystifications, but they must behave as though they did, or they must at least tolerate them in silence, or get along well with those who work with them. For this reason, however, they must live within a lie. They need not accept the lie. It is enough for them to have accepted their life with it and in it. For by this very fact, individuals confirm the system, fulfill the system, make the system, are the system.\"","answers":["Havel","Nozick","Rawls","Camus"],"answer":"Havel"},{"questionText":"\"The greengrocer and the office worker have both adapted to the conditions in which they live, but in doing so, they help to create those conditions. They do what is done, what is to be done, what must be done, but at the same time-by that very token-they confirm that it must be done in fact. They conform to a particular requirement and in so doing they themselves perpetuate that requirement.\"","answers":["Havel","Lewis","Borges","Camus"],"answer":"Havel"},{"questionText":"\"Here, by the way, is one of the most important differences between the post-totalitarian system and classical dictatorships, in which this line of conflict can still be drawn according to social class. In the post-totalitarian system, this line runs de facto through each person, for everyone in his own way is both a victim and a supporter of the system. What we understand by the system is not, therefore, a social order imposed by one group upon another, but rather something which permeates the entire society and is a factor in shaping it, something which may seem impossible to grasp or define (for it is in the nature of a mere principle), but which is expressed by the entire society as an important feature of its life.\"","answers":["Havel","Churchill","Nozick","Borges"],"answer":"Havel"},{"questionText":"\"In everyone there is some willingness to merge with the anonymous crowd and to flow comfortably along with it down the river of pseudo life. This is much more than a simple conflict between two identities. It is something far worse: it is a challenge to the very notion of identity itself.\"","answers":["Havel","Lyotard","Camus","Lewis"],"answer":"Havel"},{"questionText":"\"The essential aims of life are present naturally in every person. In everyone there is some longing for humanity's rightful dignity, for moral integrity, for free expression of being and a sense of transcendence over the world of existence. Yet, at the same time, each person is capable, to a greater or lesser degree, of coming to terms with living within the lie.\"","answers":["Havel","Lewis","Hayek","Nozick"],"answer":"Havel"},{"questionText":"\"Let us now imagine that one day something in our greengrocer snaps and he stops putting up the slogans merely to ingratiate himself. He stops voting in elections he knows are a farce. He begins to say what he really thinks at political meetings. And he even finds the strength in himself to express solidarity with those whom his conscience commands him to support. In this revolt the greengrocer steps out of living within the lie. He rejects the ritual and breaks the rules of the game. He discovers once more his suppressed identity and dignity. He gives his freedom a concrete significance. His revolt is an attempt to live within the truth.\"","answers":["Havel","Nozick","Lewis","Camus"],"answer":"Havel"},{"questionText":"\"The greengrocer has not committed a simple, individual offense, isolated in its own uniqueness, but something incomparably more serious. By breaking the rules of the game, he has disrupted the game as such. He has exposed it as a mere game. He has shattered the world of appearances, the fundamental pillar of the system. He has upset the power structure by tearing apart what holds it together.\"","answers":["Havel","Rawls","Nozick","Lyotard"],"answer":"Havel"},{"questionText":"\"He has demonstrated that living a lie is living a lie. He has broken through the exalted facade of the system and exposed the real, base foundations of power. He has said that the emperor is naked. And because the emperor is in fact naked, something extremely dangerous has happened: by his action, the greengrocer has addressed the world. He has enabled everyone to peer behind the curtain. He has shown everyone that it is possible to live within the truth.\"","answers":["Havel","Camus","Lewis","Borges"],"answer":"Havel"},{"questionText":"\"In the post-totalitarian system, therefore, living within the truth has more than a mere existential dimension (returning humanity to its inherent nature), or a noetic dimension (revealing reality as it is), or a moral dimension (setting an example for others). It also has an unambiguous political dimension. If the main pillar of the system is living a lie, then it is not surprising that the fundamental threat to it is living the truth.\"","answers":["Havel","Camus","Nozick","Rawls"],"answer":"Havel"},{"questionText":"\"... the original and most important sphere of activity, one that predetermines all the others, is simply an attempt to create and support the independent life of society as an articulated expression of living within the truth. In other words, serving truth consistently, purposefully, and articulately, and organizing this service.\"","answers":["Havel","Camus","Nozick","Hayek"],"answer":"Havel"},{"questionText":"\"you do not become a \"dissident\" just because you decide one day to take up this most unusual career. You are thrown into it by your personal sense of responsibility, combined with a complex set of external circumstances. You are cast out of the existing structures and placed in a position of conflict with them. It begins as an attempt to do your work well, and ends with being branded an enemy of society.\"","answers":["Havel","Solzhenitsyn","Hayek","Reagan"],"answer":"Havel"},{"questionText":"\"given the complex system of manipulation on which the post-totalitarian system is founded and on which it is also dependent, every free human act or expression, every attempt to live within the truth, must necessarily appear as a threat to the system....\"","answers":["Havel","Camus","Borges","Lewis"],"answer":"Havel"}].map(question => {question.mcq = false; return question})
let tempQuestionObj = {}
let questions = mcqQuestions.concat(quoteQuestions)
questions.forEach(q => tempQuestionObj[q.questionText] = {answers: q.answers, answer: q.answer, mcq: q.mcq})
questions = Object.keys(tempQuestionObj).map(k => {
    let resObj = { question: k, answer: tempQuestionObj[k].answer }

    console.log(tempQuestionObj[k].mcq)
    if (tempQuestionObj[k].mcq) {
        resObj.answers = tempQuestionObj[k].answers
        resObj.mcq = true
    }
    console.log(resObj.answers)
    return resObj
})

let questionIndex = -1

export let randomQuestion = () => {
    let index = Math.floor(Math.random() * questions.length)
    while (index == questionIndex) {
        index = Math.floor(Math.random() * questions.length)
    }
    questionIndex = index
    return questions[index]
}